Prabagara kumar R

No.165 Elim Nagar 2nd cross street, Perungudi, Chennai-600096

Contact no: +91 9710944246, E-mail: <u>praba0848@gmail.com</u>

Summary

Relevant Work Experience with a 5+ year proven track record of creating, improving, and developing IT solutions. In a previous position at Code Mantra Company, achieved 10% early completion of projects with a client satisfaction rate of 92%.

Skills

- HTML5
- CSS3
- FS6
- Bootstrap
- SASS
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- ReactJS
- Redux
- NodeJS
- Mango DE
- Express
- GI7
- MERN

EXPERIENCE

UI Developer: (Sep 2019 – June 2023) at CODEMANTRA Ltd.,

UI developer, developing web application using ReactJS. Web application Projects which are based on books management. Project Name - Collection Point, Data Extraction, Accessibility insight.

My roles and responsibility are to Produced stunning visual elements of web applications by translating UI/UX design wireframes into code while producing high quality, reusable markup using HTML5 and CSS3.

Expand features, refine code, and improve processes, producing smoother operations and enhancing user engagement

Designed dynamic and browser compatible pages using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, and JavaScript.

Ensure efficient web development by supporting designers and app developers while resolving website performance issues.

Technologies Used: Material UI, ReactJS, Redux, JavaScript, NodeJS, Express JS, Mango DB

UI Developer: (July 2018 - July 2019) at TNQ Technology Ltd.,

My role is to build e-books and make sure its responsive for all devices is fine and worked on the conversion of PSD to HTML.

Developer: (Sep 2017 – March 2018) at OMS Infotech Ltd.,

Worked on the web designing site such as, Salemdew - which is based on dengue awareness. Easanconsultancy - which is based on consultancy for Actor Easan and also worked on the billing application using Dot net.

Quality Analyst: (June 2014 - Aug 2017) at Smile Outsourcing

My role and responsibility are to Monitor Agent quality on daily basis and providing timely feedbacks to agent. Develop & maintain quality reports. Find out the errors and variance analysis. Collaborates and consults with Managers regarding current quality control issues.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Science Engineering at TJ Institute of Technology (2010 - 2014)

High School: Completed on 2010 in ST. Pius X Matriculation Higher Secondary School.

X Matriculation: Completed on 2008 in ST. Pius X Matriculation Higher Secondary School.